SERGIO MOLINA

Being a dedicated professional with a degree in Energy Engineering with experience in the areas of Data & Business analysis, solar energy production and storage technologies, my practical expertise and analytical mindset ensure the targeted development of all processes, while building and maintaining profitable relationships with clients, employees and key decision makers.



PERSON

Name Sergio Molina Address Theresienstrasse, 18 90478 Nürnberg, Germany Phone +49 176 | 84 81 97 12 Email sergi.cmolina@gmail.com Project Portfolio Link LinkedIn Link

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Project Management
- Solar Energy Engineering
- Data Analysis
- Programming & App Development
- Team Leadership & Development
- Process Optimization
- Communication

IT-SKILLS

Data Analysis & Visualization:

MS Office – Word & Excel, SQL, Tableau, Power BI, Python, VBA, DAX, Inkscape

Engineering:

PVSyst, ArcGIS, HOMER Grid, Matlab, CHEQ4, AutoCAD, SolidWorks, C++

Video & Image Editing:

Adobe – Photoshop, Premiere, After Effects & Lightroom, Photoscape X, Insta360 Studio, Filmora, GIMP

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

GestiArea | Barcelona, Spain

Business Analyst

November 2021 - July 2022

- Analyzed internal agency data to identify improvement areas and make data-driven decisions to increase efficiency
- Created and maintained dashboard reports to visualize and communicate business performance metrics to management
- Collaborated with account manager to identify KPIs and establish data tracking processes, translating in better streamlined data collection and analysis for multiple clients

Barcelona, Spain

Freelancer - Solar Energy Engineer

October 2021 - May 2022

- Design of a solar power system, a battery setup and a wiring diagram for a dental clinic in Barcelona (Clínica Dental UllDent)
- Proposal of different energy generation scenarios, for client to choose regarding initial investment and future annual savings
- Outcome: Several efficiency improvements, a design allowing for a 25-30% annual energy bill savings and 12 years return on investment

Barcelona, Spain

Freelancer - Science Teacher

September 2019 – February 2022

- Assessment of engineering students from different universities in science related subjects like calculus, linear algebra, statistics and probability, physics, coding in Python, and electrical systems
- Conduction of tutorials on how to use software like AutoCAD or SolidWorks

inQueue | Valencia, Spain

Algorithm Developer

February 2019 - October 2019

• Support with the development of an App capable to manage and optimize queue waiting times – Award-winning project of Emprendedores 2019

Gracia School | Barcelona, Spain

Assistant Teacher

May 2015 – September 2017

- Teaching science related subjects to high school students aged 15-18 on the basis of national curriculum guidelines
- Planning and implementing various educational programs as well as conducting examinations

EDUCATION

Friedrich-Alexander-Universität | Nürnberg, Germany

Master of Science - Electromobility - ACES

Since September 2022

- Focus: Artificial Intelligence and Connectivity, Deep Learning, Data Science and Data Analytics
- Advanced machine learning algorithms and techniques, enabling accurate predictive modeling and data analysis

LANGUAGES

Spanish Mother Tongue Catalan Mother Tongue English Fluent French B1 – B2 German A2 – B1

VOLUNTEERING

Mentor at the Mentoring Programme for Welcoming International Students

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya · Barcelona Tech – UPC

January 2020 – June 2020

- Responsibility for online activities of school familiarisation as well as language and cultural exchange
- Organizing events for international students

REFERENCES

Available on request

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya | Barcelona, Spain

Bachelor of Engineering – Energy Engineering

September 2017 - July 2021

- Focus: Renewable energies production systems, energy storage, electricity transmission and distribution networks, nuclear power plants, and wind power generation
- Bachelor's Thesis: Focus on a real scenario, studying the available solar resource on the rooftops of public administration buildings in the municipality of Badalona with the intent to connect them to the Spanish Electricity Network. Thesis with Highest Honors.
- Recognized with a total of 240 ECTS by the Bologna Process

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya | Barcelona, Spain

Bachelor of Engineering – Aerospace Engineering *No Degree*

September 2014 - June 2016

 Focus: Navigation, surveillance systems, flight physics and mechanics, meteorology, electronic instrumentation, and flight control systems

CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES

Data Analyst in Python

March 2022

 Preparation and extraction of data by querying databases with SQL, creating insightful data visualization, performing descriptive and predictive statistical analysis, complex statistical analysis of large datasets, as well as SQL queries and web-scraping to explore and extract data from databases and websites

Data Scientist in Python

Jan 2022

- Object-oriented and functional programming with Python
- Usage of libraries like scikit-learn, Matplotlib, NumPy, and pandas
- Web scraping and SQL queries, deep learning and machine learning, and predictive analysis

Business Analyst

July 2021

 Data analysis in Excel, exploring and extracting data from datasets using SQL, present insights using dashboards and visualizations in Power BI